Girkin is a terrorist no how not that is I am a
гиркин террорист нет как нет то есть Я
terrorist if I seize in Russia and
террорист если я захвачу в России а
when a citizen of Russia seizes in
когда гражданин России захватывает в
Ukraine knowledge he is not a terrorist Well, the World Cup is
Украине знание он не террорист Да ну ЧМ
different in that Belgorod was not
разни в том что Белгороду ничего не
threatened And what threatened Slavyansk in
угрожало А что угрожало славянску в
Belgorod there is no Avenue of Angels Wait,
Белгороде нету алеи ангелов Подождите а
what is the Avenue of Angels  it just appeared as a
что алея Ангелов как раз и появилась в
result of the invasion of these Russian
результате вторжения вот этих российских
boogeymen because the war started
бояков из-за того что началась война
good afternoon Hello, I am from Ukraine, the
добрый день Здравствуйте я из Украины
city of Khmelnitsky And you I am from Russia, the city of
город Хмельницкий А вы Я из России город
Kemeron, look how you personally
кемерон вот смотрите вы лично как
support the Russian invasion of Ukraine
поддерживаете вторжение России в Украину
that
которое
happened no no I understand because  I'm
произошло нет нет понял потому что я вот
looking for people who support and
ищу людей которые поддерживают и
I ask their opinion so why do
спрашиваю их мнение так а вот почему вот
others support And you won't support
другие поддерживают А вы не поддержите
What is your motivation that you Well I'm for
вот Какая ваша мотивация что вы Ну я за
peace you
мир
understand I'm for peace Well yes Why are
понимаете я за мир Ну да Почему другие
n't others For
не За
peace let's say you have a neighbor there
мир вот условно у вас там есть сосед
for example  So why did he somehow become for war?
например Так почему он как-то за войну
In your opinion, it
Стал вот по вашему мнению Мне
seems to me that someone would say I want
кажется вот чтобы кто-то говорил Я хочу
war, bloodshed, I don’t know who I
войны кровопролития это я не знаю кем
should be, I just  I understand why this
надо быть я просто понимаю почему это
happened But if well the collapse of the
произошло Но если бы ну распад
Soviet Union That is, you are now
Советского Союза То есть вы сейчас
attacking from under the Soviet Union No
напали на из пода Советского Союза Нет
well these are unfinished processes that are
ну это незавершённые процессы которые
now happening throughout the CIS
сейчас происходят по всему СНГ
Azerbaijan Armenia and so on Georgia
Азербайджан Армения и и так далее Грузия
Abkhazia This is all some kind of
Абхазия Вот это всё не какой
unfinished process look we  uh
незавершённый процесс вот смотрите мы ээ
separated In ninety-first year yes
отделились В девяносто первом году да
left the republic So you also declared in
вышли республика Так вы объявили тоже в
ninety Russia declared its
девяностом году Россия объявила свой
sovereignty so that is Russia also
суверенитет так то есть Россия тоже
left the Soviet Union it turns out that
вышла из Советского Союза получается что
we lived as an independent state and
мы жили жили независимым государством и
then Russia attacked us No at all everything is
тут на нас Россия напала Нет вообще вс
not so And how why  arestovich
не так А как почему арестович это
predicted it and there Zherino everyone
предсказал и там жерино все
predicted that this conflict
предсказывали что этот конфликт
would happen Why do you say that it is
будет Почему Вот вы говорите что это
logical Sevastopol the Russian fleet was in
логично Севастополь русский флот был в
Sevastopol correctly on lease
Севастополе правильно в аренде
Yes there was a coup
Да случился переворот
Well it is a coup d'etat no
Ну это государственный переворот нет
violent seizure of power what violent
насильственный захват власти какой
And what was there
насильственный А что там было
violent seizure of power what kind of
насильственный захват власти какой какую
power was seized by violence Well, it's as
власть захватили насильство Ну вы как
if you don't know no I don't know I'm from Ukraine
будто не знаете не не знаю я из Украины
I know my history in general I'm
я историю свою знаю в общем я
telling And now he comes about
рассказываю Вот и сейчас приходит про
the West  government for example to
Западное правительство например на
Ukraine and put NATO bases in Sevastopol
Украину и ставят базы НАТО в Севастополе
Russia, let's say, and what
Росси допустим и какая
Rossini some NATO So you already have NATO right next
Россини неком НАТО Так у вас и так под
door in Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, now
боком НАТО в Эстонии Латвии Литве теперь
in Finland there will be more, well, yes, but the fleet
в Финляндии будет ещё ну это да Но флот
was in Sevastopol and now there will be a
Стоял в Севастополе а там сейчас будут
NATO base there for Putin  is it profitable or
стоять база НАТО Путину это выгодно или
not And that in Russia the fleet should have been
нет И что в России флот должен был
stationed only Until the twenty-seventh year Yes
стоять токо До двадцать седьмого года Да
Yeah and then they should have taken their
Угу и потом должны были забрать свой
fleet So what And what if we have an
флот Ну и что А какая раз вот у нас есть
independent country We want to make the
независимая страна мы Какие хотим базы
kind of bases we want here We don't tell you
такие тут и делать Мы же вам не
we will tell you what bases you should make
расскажем Какие Вам базы делать
Well, if you think that this is some kind of
Ну если вы думаете что это какой-то
rosy world and everyone lives in peace and
розовый мир и все живут в мире и
harmony, everyone does what they want, no one
согласия все делают что хотят ни кого
has their own personal interests, and so on,
нет своих личных интересов и так далее
then it turns out that you are not quite for peace, so
То вы получается не совсем За мир так
why do you find an excuse?
почему то есть вы находите оправдание
I can understand what this aggression is
получается я могу понять из чего она
made up of, that it is not as you say
складывается что не как вы говорите
Putin went crazy at one moment and attacked
Путин сошл с ума в один момент и напал
Ukraine And who is Sol then Let's do it
на Украину А кто Сол тогда Вот давайте
this way, who is to blame for this
так кто виноватый в этой
war This will not answer I don't think that
войне Это не ответит Я не думаю что
anyone here  guilty Well, as it is,
здесь кто-то виноват Ну как есть ту
look if  here Russia attacked
смотрите если вот Россия напала на
Ukraine Who is to blame specifically what
Украину Кто виноват конкретно какие
people Well look in the fourteenth year
люди Ну смотрите в четырнадцатом году
when Donetsk Luhansk region just
когда Донецкая Луганская область просто
wanted federal status for themselves so that they
хотели себе Федеративный статус чтобы
wanted Donetsk Luhansk region did not
хотели донецко Луганская область не
want any federal status
хотели никакой Федеративной статус
Don't
Не
look there were pro-Russian militants
смотрите там были пророссийские боевики
Yes who came from Russia Girkin
Да которые пришли из России гиркин
Strelkov Yes they captured there  territories it
стрелков Да захватили там территории это
was already after And when tell
было уже после А когда скажите тогда
me then when can you people initially in
когда можете мне народ изначально в
Donetsk Lugansk region you will
донецко Луганской области вы будете
now deny that there about Russian
сейчас отрицать что там про Российские
sentiments a small number of people
настроения небольшое количество людей
were yes Russian sentiments and that a
были да российские настроения и что
small good look there is Let's
небольшое хоро смотрите есть Давайте так
show me for example some decision
покажите мне например какое-то решение
Lugansk  regional council, that is,
Луганского областного совета то есть
deputies who represent the entire
депутатов которые представляют всё
population elected legally or
население избранных законно или
Donetsk regional council, that is, all
Донецкого областного совета то есть всех
deputies of the Donetsk region elected
депутатов Донецкой области избранных
legally by the entire population yes About some kind of
законно всем населением да О какой-то
branch of the Federation there is
вот там отделении там Федерации что-то
nothing like that Why not Well, we
нету такого Почему нет Ну мы же сейчас
won't now I will now  I shouldn't google there to
не будем Я сейчас не должен гуглить там
look you say No I say there is So
искать вы говорите Нет я говорю есть Так
and I tell you that there is not If you are So
а я вам говорю что нет Если вы есть Так
show me you're not the first one who is like that The thing is
покажите вы же не первый кто тако Дело в
that  while you are searching Yes I will tell you how it
том что пока вы ищете Да скажу вам как
was Yes That is to say there was a small part of
было да То есть были небольшая часть
pro-Russian protesters Yes they wanted the
пророссийских митингующих Да они хотели
regional Council to accept such a thing the
чтобы областной Совет принял такую вещь
regional Council said no we
областной Совет сказал что нет мы не
will not accept such a thing because we do not
будем принимать такое потому что мы не
agree We do the will of the entire population of
согласны Мы делаем волю всего население
Donetsk or Luhansk
Донецкой или Луганской
region then  armed people took them
обла потом взяли вооружённые люди пришли
and came and said that they will now be the power
да и сказали что они теперь будут власть
from
из
Russia well this is now a long time to look for me
России ну это сейчас долго искать мне
now fresh highlights Here that's what
сейчас свежее высвечивает Вот то
look Yes if you assert something then
смотрите Да вы если что-то утверждаете
prepare yourself as you so the voice
то подготовьтесь так как вы так голос
prepared for a conversation with you How can I
готовился к разговору с вами Как я могу
my theses  prepare there on paper Well,
свои тезисы подготовить там на бумаг Так
well, well, then don't tell us
ну да ну так вы тогда не рассказывайте
with theses that you're not ready for,
тезисами которы к которым вы не готовы
that's why you say
вот на основании чего вы говорите
that Lugansk and Donetsk region wanted
что лугански и Донецкая область хотели
something, individual people in Donetsk
что-то отдельные люди в Донецкой
Lugansk region maybe wanted something
Луганской области может что-то и хотели
And how did Donetsk  Luhansk region wanted
А как Донецкая Луганская область хотела
Donetsk Luhansk region is represented by the
донецку луганскую область представляет
official elected body Yes their
официальный избранный орган Да их
regional Council Luhansk and regional
областной Совет Луганский и областной
Council of Donetsk region
Совет Донецкой области никаких таких
they did not make any such decisions militants who
решений они не принимали боевики которые
came they are the opposite  dissolved this
пришли они наоборот распустили этот
council the law of elected deputies
совет закон избранных депутатов
some were killed Well I understand your
некоторых убили Ну я понимаю вашу
rhetoric and For example if I now say
риторику и Например если я сейчас скажу
there about ATO you will start saying that they
там про ато вы начнёте говорить что
wanted to kill
это хотели убить
Lie down Come on Tell me and I will tell you
Лежите Давайте Вот скажите и я скажу вам
yes to
да
us Good Here And when according to you ATO
нам Хорош Вот А когда по вашему ато
started there is no goal ATO  were What Well
начали нет цели ато были Какими Ну
look April 12, 2014 Girkin with a
смотрите 12 апреля 2014 года гиркин с
detachment Yes captured crossed the border
отрядом Да захватил перешёл границу
armed with a grenade launcher Yes
вооружённый гранатомёта Да
automatic weapons captured the city of
автоматическое оружие захватили город
Slavyansk so removed the
Славянске так сместили
mayor of some criminal put that
мэра какого-то уголовника поставили что
he will now be the mayor and Gorlovka was also
он теперь будет мром и Горловку также
captured in Gorlovka killed a deputy
захватили в Горловке убили депутата
by the way deputy of the city council
между прочим депутата городского совета
you can  look at and naturally
можете посмотреть во и естественно
they did an anti-terrorist operation the
сделали антитеррористическую операцию
National Security and Defense Council met in the evening of the dgo date and
национальной безопасности и обороны и
made a decision Yes about an
принял решение Да об
anti-terrorist operation because
антитеррористической операции потому что
terrorists if look if I take
террористы если смотрите если я возьму
people and we capture for example the city of
людей и мы захватим например э город
Belgorod so armed here is the
Белгород так вооружённого вот отделение
police department this is not a war Yes this is a  then don't
полиции это не война Да это а то Не
look wait again again again
смотрите Подождите ещё раз ещё раз ещё
again let's not cut if I  I will
раз давайте не среза если я возьму
take the city of Belgorod So with
захвачу город Белгород Так с отрядами
some detachments so I will be a
какими-то так я буду
terrorist m yes yes That is, Girkin
террористом м да да Вот то есть гиркин
was a
был
terrorist
террористом
M not ready to answer how not ready Well,
М не готов ответить как не готов Ну
look absolutely if I crossed the border
смотри абсолютно если Я перешёл границу
into your country and captured a
в вашу страну и захватил с вооружённым
police station with an armed detachment, for example, with
отрядом отделение полиции например с
machine guns  in Belgorod so I am a terrorist
автоматами в Белгороде так Я террорист
you said Yes now I
вы сказали Да теперь я симметрично
say symmetrically if Girkin entered
говорю если гиркин зашёл
when the Soviet army entered Berlin they are a
когда Советская армия вошла в Берлин они
terrorist what
террорист что
about
о
it then Girkin is absolutely Mirror
йте то гиркин абсолютно Зеркальная
situation Girkin entered Ukraine
ситуация гиркин зашёл в Украину
captured in Mirny city Slavensk where there
захватили в Мирном городе славенск где
was nothing at all Yes we have no
вообще ничего не было Да никаких у нас
roads  there was no shooting nothing yes that
дор никаких стрельб ничего не было да то
is he captured the city he is a terrorist
есть захватил город он террорист
terrorist Well I ask you And when the
террорист Ну я вас спрашиваю А когда
Soviet
Советская
army Rory is a terrorist or not Girkin is a
армия Рори террорист или нет гиркин
terrorist no how no that is I am a
террорист нет как нет то есть Я
terrorist if I capture in Russia and
террорист если я захвачу в России а
when a citizen of Russia captures in
когда гражданин России захватывает в
Ukraine you know he is not a terrorist  yes,
Украине зна он не террорист да раз в том
since Belgorod was not threatened by anything. And what
что Белгороду ничего не угрожало А что
threatened slans
угрожало сланс
Belgorod is not there. Ale
Белгороде нету Але
angels of these grew from the fact that the
ангелов жения эти рос из того что
war began tell me before Girkin's arrival
война скажите мне до прихода гиркина
at least one victim in Donbass Tell
хоть одну жертву на Донбассе Скажите Вы
me will you answer the
мне ответите на
question whether fascist Germany should have been
вопрос фашистскую Германию надо было
liberated or not If 90% of the population
освобождать или нет Если 90% населения
were for there was a war look the Third
были за там была война смотрите Третий
Reich attacked other countries Naturally
рейх напал на другие стра Естественно
that  other countries
что другие страны
otvovo kami came no look It
отвово ками приходил нет смотри Это
was a war here uh we are now here it was the
война была вот ээ мы сейчас вот это была
Second World War everything is clear there yes
Вторая мировая война там всё понятно да
That is you attacked now you were attacked And
То есть вы напали теперь на вас напали А
in Slavensk the city of Slavensk Strelkov entered
в славенск город славенск стрелков зашёл
because of which there was no alley of angels
из-за чего никакой алеи ангелов не было
at all  there was no shooting
вообще никаких стрельб не было Никто с
No one was running around with a machine gun They were even the first people
автоматом не бегал даже это первые люди
who came
которые пришли
armed That is, it all started with them
вооружённые то есть с них всё и началось
And then there was a stream of these
И дальше ещё начался поток вот этих
Russian uh disguised
российских ээ переодетых да
men like that That's how he is a
таких угу мужичков так Вот так он
terrorist That's why you don't consider him a
террорист Вот почему вы не считаете его
terrorist consider me  terrorist
террористом меня считайте террористом
if I come to Belgorod For example,
если я приду в Белгород Вот например
let's do it in Belgorod too, for
давайте так в Белгороде тоже там
example, there are rallies against Putin, for
например митинги против Путина так
example, someone for  Navalny someone for
например кто-то за Навального кто-то за
Putin and so 10 people say we
Путина так и вот 10 человек говорит мы
want to separate there, for example,
хотим там короче отделяться там например
from Russia, I take a detachment of 50 people and
от России я беру отряд там 50 человек и
we capture the city of Valuyki, for example, in the
мы захватываем город Валуйки например
Belgorod region, so we kill people, we
белгородскою область так убиваем людей
kill a city council deputy, I
убиваем депутата городского совета я
will be a terrorist, you have no
буду террористом буду Вы же не
doubt  in
сомневаетесь в
this if now absolutely the same
этом если теперь абсолютно то самое
I ask you about Girkin you are for peace but
спрашиваю вас про гиркина вы за мир но
you start something no no he is not a
вы что-то начинаете нет нет он не
terrorist And who is he
террорист А кто он
then an employee of the special services Well that is he
тогда работник спецслужб Ну а то есть он
officially yes like not a terrorist And
официально да типа не террорист А
official
официаль
already then it turns out you have a different position
вже то получается ва иная позиция вы
like for peace but somehow here we
вроде за мир но как-то вот тут мы
start when on the shelves not quite For
начинаем когда по полочкам не совсем За
peace it turns out you are legitimizing
мир получается вы легитимирующая
I talked with people of Simferopol here is the head of
я общался с людьми Симферополя вот заком
55 years And what is the point of the army look
55 лет И какой смысл рать смотрите
now you can Here they held a referendum in
сейчас можете Вот провели референдум в
Kherson so in the occupied So you
Херсоне так в оккупированном Так вы
consider this
считаете это
a referendum  in Kherson Yes, I don't know
референдумом в Херсоне Да я не знаю
the mood of the people in Kherson No, look,
настроени людей в Херсоне Не ну смотрите
what is occupied now  maybe there
вот сейчас оккупированный какое может
is a mood when there are armed
быть настроение когда там вооружённые
people there and there is no law they can
Люди так и нету никакого закона могут
grab you and take you under
тебя схватить и на под
Yes, no one is missing there Yes, if there is no one
Да никого там не хватает Да если как не
missing, look at the first days what kind of
хватает смотрите первые дни какие были
performances there were in Kherson Yes, where did they
выступления в Херсоне Да куда они
go Where did they go immediately surrendered No,
делись Куда делись сразу сдали Не ну
where did the people go who  everyone came out
куда делись люди которые все выходили Да
with flags against Russian troops,
с флагами против российских войск так
so in Crimea from February 26 to
вот по Крыму с 26 на
27, Russian special forces
27 февраля так российский спецназ
seized the Crimean parliament,
захватил парламент Крыма
some other state, non-
ещё некоторые государствен не
state,
государственные вот там управленческие
administrative buildings, they put
эти ээ здания так поставили в аэропорты
their military in airports everywhere, everywhere,
всюду всюду всюду своих э военных так то
so Russia invaded  the beginning was like that
есть Россия сделала вторжение начало так
on the night of February 26-27 everything that
2 ше в ночь с 26 на 27 февраля всё что
followed happened under
дальше это уже происходило под
occupation what kind of referendum can we
оккупацией про какой референдум мы можем
talk about Yes, first of all, in the Constitution of
говорить Да во-первых в Конституции
Ukraine and in the Constitution of Crimea Yes,
Украины и в Конституции Крыма Да вот
if you took the Constitution of Crimea, in
если вы взяли бы Конституцию Крыма в
its first article there was something  that Crimea is an
первой статье её было что что Крым есть
integral part of Ukraine
неотъемлемой частью Украины
so no referendums nothing this is one that
так никаких референдумов ничего это раз
is there is no such provision in Ukrainian
то есть нет в украинском
legislation
законодательстве
on referendums one
такой положение о референдумах раз
second if on
вторые если 26
February 26 the Russian invaders  captured
февраля захватчики российские захватили
Crimea, removed the head of the Crimean parliament there.
Крым сместили там главу парламента Крыма
Yes, and then they already held some kind of
вроде и дальше уже делали какой-то там
referendum themselves. I can also come to Belgorod
референдум сами я тоже могу в Белгороде
with a machine gun to hold a referendum and show that
прийти с автоматом провести показать что
I held a referendum and that Belgorod is
я провёл референдум и что Белгород Сане
now
теперь
mine.
моим
Look at Crimea. Under what conditions did it become
смотрите Крым При каких условиях стал
the territory of Ukraine? What
территорией Украины какая
difference does it make?  what time Well look
разница как какая раз Ну смотри Вот
Let's do it this way When
давайте так Когда образовалось
the state of Ukraine was formed like that August 24 of that
государство Украина так 24 августа дего
year When the state of
года Когда образовалось государство
Russia was formed also in the nineties like that Russian
России тоже в девяностых так Российская
Federation
Федерация
No well Under what conditions was there any
Нет ну При каких условиях был какая
difference when look at it Crimea In ninety-
разница при смотрите он Крым В девяносто
first year So Crimea was part of
первом году Так Крым был в составе
Ukraine you understand  then no one knew
Украины вы понимаете тогда никто не знал
that the Soviet Union would fall apart again
что Советский Союз развалится ещё раз
look and how
смотри а а как
Kaliningrad ended up in Russia How
в состав России попал Калининград Как
some Buryatia ended up there, that is,
попал какие-то там Бурятии всё то есть
that was the story Yes, there were
вот история была Да там переходил
territories transferred there In
переходили территории вот В девяносто
1991 So a new state was formed, the
первом году Так э образовались новое
Russian Federation, a new one
государства Российская Федерация новое
state of Ukraine Ukraine they were not
государство э Украи Украина они не
formed this happened because of the collapse of the
образовались это произошло из-за распада
Soviet Union they were formed they but the
Советского Союза они образовались они но
borders were outlined again look
границы были очерчены ещё раз смотрите
here it was  the state
вот было государство
once created these some
когда-то создали эти некоторые
states created the Soviet Union
государства создали Советский Союз
So now when the Soviet Union collapsed the
Так теперь когда Советский Союз распался
states became independent they are you
государства стали независимы они вот вы
Russia you in the nineties
Россия вы в девяностом году
proclaimed even earlier than Ukraine
провозгласили ещё раньше чем Украина
proclaimed the declaration of
провозгласили декларацию про
state sovereignty of the Russian
государственный суверенитет Российской
Federation
Федерации
also left the
вышли тоже из
USSR Russia that is the state of the USSR is not
СССР России то есть государство СССР не
became became 15 new states
стало Стало 15 новых государст
So you have your own borders we have our own
Так у вас свои границы у нас свои
borders we had an agreement with you from
границы у нас был с вами договор от
ninety-seventh year on the recognition of
девяносто седьмого года о признании
borders there was an agreement on friendship and
границ там договор о дружбе и
cooperation it was called there everything
сотрудничестве назывался там чётко всё
was clearly spelled out What's the problem What
было прописано Да в чём проблема Какая
difference does it make what and when who has  everything was
разница что и когда у кого было всё было
clearly spelled out in the Minsk agreements
чётко прописано и в минских соглашениях
Why for example look at Belgorod
Почему з на например смотрите Белгород
so Belgorod was once Ukrainian
так Белгород когда-то был украинской
territory at the beginning of the 10th century we don't
территория в начале X столетия мы же не
say Give us
говорим Отдайте нам
Belgorod is
Белгород
true that's why when you are told
правда тобто Почему вы когда вам говорят
that you occupied Crimea And you start
что вы оккупировали Крым А вы начинаете
and he  I was there once in the Russian
а он когда-то был там в Российской
Empire,
империи
and what does this have to do with the Russian Federation
причём Причём тут к Российской Федерации
that exists
которая есть
now, that is, you, you are not For peace,
сейчас то есть вы вы не За мир
you see, you start piling on
вы видите вы начинаете наваливать
excuses So  why did they take away Crimea Yes,
оправдания Так почему Крым отжали Да
why Because I don't live in rose-colored
почему Потому что я не живу в розовых
glasses now Putin is saying that he is crazy and
очках сейчас говорит Путин сумасшедший
attacked poor Ukraine if only
напал на бедную Украину вот
he would negotiate with all countries,
договаривался бы он со всеми странами
damn, and with America, we would be friends with everyone,
блин и с Америкой со всеми дружили бы
how good it would be, in general, good but what
как хорошо бы было вообще хорошо а вот
if you don't have rose-colored glasses there  and there are green ones
если у вас там не розовые а там зелёные
or what kind of glasses do you have? No, but in
или какие у вас Очки не так а вот в
your glasses what kind of view Who is to blame?
ваших очках что вид Кто виноват вот
Name the name of who is to blame over there. Well, do you
Назовите фамилию кто виноват воне Ну вы
seriously think that this is such a simple
серьёзно думаете что это такой простой
question that you can say he is to
вопрос что можно сказать он
blame, he made a decision. So what
виноват же принял решение Так а какое
decision? Well, the decision to introduce  troops to
решение Ну решение о вводе войск в
Ukraine And who made the decision to withdraw from the
Украину А кто принял решение выйти из
negotiations not once again who made
переговоров не ещё раз кто принял
the decision to introduce troops into Ukraine
решение ввести войска в Украину
Who is an independent state Ukraine
Кто есть независимое государство Украина
is an independent state Russia So
есть независимое государство Россия Так
who made the decision Zhirinovsky the deceased made the decision
кто принял Жириновский покойный принял
who is responsible for
кто ответственный за
this for the special operation Russia and Specifically in
это за спецоперацию Россия а Конкретно в
personalities I do not know who  Putin made this
личностях я не знаю кто принимал это
decision Why were you there
решение Путин А почему вы там были что
in the
ли в
Kremlin? He signed it, he announced it,
Кремле он же подписывал он же объявлял
he approved it, he is the Supreme
одобрил он Верховный
Commander-in-Chief. So it turns out that
главнокомандующий То есть получается
Putin and the entire
Путин и весь Совет
Federation Council are burning,
Федерации ю сгори
what are we even talking about?  I think it's
про что мы говорим вообще я думаю это
America's fault
Америка виновата потому
because Kosovo Kosovo Why can Kosovo
что Косово Косово Почему Косово может
separate and say that we are like this here
отделиться и сказать мы вот такие здесь
we are independent and the DPR is not again So I
мы независимые а ДНР нет ещ раз Значит я
understood correctly VNII on
правильно понял внии на
Ukraine you won't get me out that I will say that
Укра меня не вытащите что я скажу что
Putin is guilty and no well you look at you before
Путин виноват и не ну вы смотри вы перед
that  they said yes Putin and the people
этим сказали что да Виноват Путин и люди
around Putin are to blame but now you are
там возле Путина но теперь Вы снова
starting again said Vi on you I said that
начинаете сказал Ви на вас я сказал что
they approved the decision to start
они одобрили решение о начале
a special operation Yeah That is they Let's
спецоперации Ага То есть они Давайте ещё
come back then that means they they made
тогда вернёмся значит они они приняли
this decision They are responsible for it
это решение Они несут за него
So that means Well  they are
ответственность Так значит Ну они
to blame for this
виноваты в этой
war in the attack on Ukraine in the introduction of
войне в нападении на Украину в введении
troops into Ukraine Who is
войск в Украину Кто
to blame Well, I would not reason in such
виноват Ну я бы не рассуждал такими
categories wine Well, look, they are
категори вино Ну как ну смотрите вот
killing a bunch of people who is to blame for the death of
убивают кучу людей кто виноват в смерти
these people who introduced troops into
этих людей кто ввёл войска в
Ukraine I
Украину Я же
said America
сказал Америка
No and you  you can't squeeze out you're afraid to
Нет а вы не можете выдавить Боитесь
just say Putin is guilty exactly
просто сказать Путин виноват именно
this phrase yes you're afraid that you don't want
такую фразу Да Боитесь что вами Не хочу
to say something that is you understand everything
произносить что то есть вы понимаете все
you're afraid that the FSB will come for you will finger you
Боитесь Что за вами придёт ФСБ будет вам
no no  I'm afraid That is, all
Не не боюсь Вот то есть все что-то
the Russians are
россияне они
pushing it
спихнуть
to comment on chess, is it easy or
комментировать шахматы это легко или
not, maybe not, well, just
нет может не ну вот просто любого
take any person out on the street and have him
человека на улиц взять и чтобы он
comment on chess, there's some kind of
комментировал шахматы там какая-то там
protection there, look, I'm like chess,
защита смотрите вот я как шахмати
look, what am I talking about?  it's complicated
смотрите я вам про что говор это сложно
and Geopolitics is a million times more complicated and
а Геополитика в миллион раз сложнее и то
what you One says Putin is to blame the other
что вы Один говорит Путин виноват другой
says Zelensky is to blame you understand the truth
говорит Зеленский виноват понимаете исти
look look yes But those things that
смотри смотрите да Но те вещи которые
you want you affirm and those that you don't
вам хочется вы утверждаете а которые не
want you say Oh I'm a simple person
хочется вы говорите Ой я простой человек
I can't understand them Yes here  that's how it
я не могу разбираться в них Да тут так
turns out I'm not just saying that everything is
получается Не я просто утверждаю что всё
much more complicated than you want to say that
намного сложнее чем хотите выдать вы что
there is some crazy ruler
есть какой-то сумасшедший правитель
who decided to attack poor Ukraine and
который решил бедную Украину напасть и
that there were never any prerequisites for this
что никогда не было вытекающих из этого
and so on You want to
предпосылок и так далее Вы хотите это
exclude this That is, you are now saying
исключить То есть вы сейчас вы говорите
that this  everything is complicated but you will definitely
что это всё сложно но вот это Вы точно
pile on this, what I am piling on here as you
навалите что тут я наваливаю как вы
say, what is not so
говорите то что здесь нету такого
simple here is that one person came
простого что один человек вот ему пришла
up with an idea to do this in the fourteenth year
идея в голову там в четырнадцатом году
And everything all started there are
это сделать И всё всё началось есть
prerequisites for this Well, okay, but for
предпосылки этому Ну хорошо а вот
example, let's take the Second World
например возьмём Давайте Вторая мировая
War, so Hitler attacked as part of the
война так вот Гитлер напал на в рамках
Second World War, he attacked the
Второй мировой войны напал там на
Soviet Union, for example, he attacked Poland, he attacked
Советский Союз например на Польшу напал
there, he also attacked So who is
там ещ нападал Так кто
to blame for these attacks, Hitler or
виноват в этих нападениях Гитлер или
some
какие-то
prerequisites here fascism is to blame Well yes
предпосылки здесь виноват фашизм Ну да
here too there are prerequisites that in what
тут тоже есть предпосылки что в каком
environment Hitler grew up fascism is not fascism
Гитлер рос окружении фашизм не фашизм
all this is not just like that not in one day
всё это же не просто так не в один день
You just want to say that all this
Вы просто хотите сказать что это всё в
appeared in one day that here is who is
один день появилось что вот е Вот кто
to blame for
виноват в
Germany's attack on  Soviet Union
нападении Германии на Советский Союз
America Stalin or
Америка Сталин или
Hitler Hitler Hitler we clearly you will say
Гитлер Гитлер Гитлер мы чётко вы скажете
And why then Putin not absolutely
А почему тогда Путин не вот абсолютно
I like it You see what I am
вот мне нравится Вы видите к чему я вас
leading you to that is because I see perfectly well
подвожу то есть потому я прекрасно вижу
that you want me to say what I was
что Вы хотите чтобы я сказал о чём я
thinking I will not do that Well  that's why
думал я так не буду Ну вот почему вот
look here you see and you
смотрите вы тут видите и вы чётко
speak clearly and here you start Who is to blame for the
говорите а тут вы начинаете Кто виноват
Volyn massacre Why did so many Poles
Волынской резне Почему столько Поляков
die in the Volyn massacre Yes look
умерло в Волынской резне Да смотрите
Volyn massacre If you know yes
Волынская Резня Если вы знаете да то
then there were territories where it was mixed
есть там были территории где смешано
Ukrainian and Polish populations and
украинское и польское население так и
there acted both the Ukrainian insurgent
там действовали и украинско повстанская
army and the army of the Kryv so there
армия и армия крыва так это были там
were mutual ethnic
были взаимные взаем взаимные этнические
conflicts between Poles and Ukrainians
конфликты между поляками и украинцами
so there were Poles who killed
так были и поляки которые убивали
Ukrainians and there were Ukrainians who
украинцев и были украинцы которые
killed Poles Yes this is a difficult page in
убивали поляки Да это тяжёлая страница
the history of Ukrainian-Polish
истории украинско польских
relations  from Ukraine how do you
взаимоотношений с Украин откуда вы
know that
знаете что сначала
you first figured out geopolitics so much I'm watching
вы в геополитике так разобрались смотрю
Yes no I
Да нет я фильм
watched the film Or maybe you didn't watch exactly that kind of
просмотрел А может вы не совсем такой
film Maybe you watched a
фильм смотрели Может вы смотрели
propaganda film that is you see it
пропагандистский то есть видите у вас
turned on where you need it You turn it on and
включился где вам нужно Вы включаете и
with one hundred percent certainty you Burn
точно со стопроцентной вы Горите
Ukrainians are the first yes  that is, there
украинцы первые да то есть там тяжёлые
were difficult relations there, yes now Ukraine and
были отношения да сейчас Украина и
Poland, yes they have found a common denominator in
Польша да они нашли общий знаменатель во
many of these issues, yes we fought
многих этих вопросах Да были мы воевали
with the Poles, there was such a
с поляками было такое
thing, yes Bandera is a hero of Ukraine, a hero of Ukraine,
даен Бандера герой Украины герой Украины
yes he fought, well, he didn't fight, but he, um, sort of
да воевал Ну не воевал а он Ээ как бы
headed an organization that fought
возглавлял организацию которая боролась
for independence  Ukraine
за независимость Украины
Yeah And what do you want to say about the bandana?
Угу А что вы хотите про бандане сказать
And what is the independence of Ukraine if he
А в чём независимость Украины если он
agreed on everything with the German
договаривался обо всём с немецким
leadership? A  can you tell me where he
руководством А можете скать где он
negotiated with the German leadership
договаривался с немецким руководством
if he is the opposite Germans He was put in the
если он наоборот немцы Его посадили в
concentration camp Ani and they did not let him out did not
концлагерь Ани а они его не выпускали не
let him out Look where they
выпускали Вот посмотри Куда
let Bandera out the
выпускали бандеру выпустили сами же
Germans themselves let him out when
немцы когда
you tell me a year Well, yeah, damn, you see I
вам год сказать Ну да блин видите я я же
didn't prepare that we have Potry  you are so clear
не готовил что у нас Потри вы так чётко
Let's then we need this somehow so
Давайте тогда этот нам нужно как-то
that I get ready Yes, here I took a pack of
чтобы я подготовился Да тут взял пачку
paper and this you see You You say here
бумаги и этот видите Вы Вы говорите тут
everything is not in rose-colored glasses it's
всё не в розовых очках это короче очень
all very complicated in short and then you start Volyn
всё сложно а тут начинаете Волынская
Massacre Bandera and there there says Poa Oh
Резня Бандера а к там там говорит Поа Ой
I  in short, he wasn't
я короче там не
prepared there No, I'm telling you, look, you don't
подготовился Нет я вам говорю смотри не
understand You're just talking about the Question
понимаете Вы просто говорите про Вопрос
What caused this war Who is to blame
Из чего появилась эта война кто виноват
You want to say that there is one
вы хотите сказать что вот есть один
person in the Armed Forces because of the scoundrels there are several of
человек ВС изза негоди там несколько у
you Not only Putin But many more yes And
вас Да не только Путина А ещё много да А
I'm just saying  that this question is very
я просто говорю что этот вопрос очень
complicated No, how complicated is it Yes, but here it
сложный Не ну как он сложный Да но тут
is clear that Putin is guilty, you are guilty,
чётко Путин виноват виноват вы виноваты
that's why we are sorting it out now, yes,
вот по вас Мы разбираемся сейчас да
guilty Or wine as a citizen of the luxury
винова Или вино как гражданин роско
Federation of
Федерации
your state you bear  how do you not bear
своего государство несёте как не несёте
No, you do bear that's exactly it Yes, for some reason
Нет несёте вот именно Да почему-то
you are the owner of a passport a passport
вы обладатель паспорта паспорт
imposes rights and obligations on you you
накладывает в вас права и обязанности вы
elect the government you authorize it that's
избирает власть вы её уполномочивает вот
another Look, you said this another
ещё Смотрите вот вы се сказали ещё такой
interesting question Ukrainians like to
интересный вопрос вот любят украинцы
say for example there is no
говорить например нету никакой
democracy in Russia Elections are  filkino
демократии в России Выборы это филькино
literacy they don't exist and then the next thesis
грамота их нету а потом следующий тезис
you chose Putin this bloody king
вы выбрали Путина этого кровавого царя
So do we have elections or not we are
Так у нас есть выборы или нет мы
democratic TM and Let's So you as a
демократическим ТМ и Давайте Так вы как
citizen of the Russian Federation you are
гражданин Российской Федерации вы несёте
responsible for the result for the
ответственность за э результат за
activities of your country just like the
деятельность своей страны так же как
Germans still do  are
немцы так до сих пор несут
responsible for the actions of Nazi
ответственность за действия гитлеровской
Germany,
Германии
however, I think this is wrong. Well, we
правда я считаю это неправильно Ну мы
can assume that children should
считать можем де чтобы дети
pay for the sins of their fathers and grandfathers.
расплачивались за грехи там отцов дедов
Well, look, and they pay. Yes, that is, if, for
Ну смотри и выплачивают да то есть если
example, their
например ихние
grandfathers destroyed
деды уничтожали там
neighboring countries, then the children pay,
соседние страны туда и дети выплачивают
essentially, from the country's economy. Here they are.
по сути с экономики страны здесь они
what does this have to do with it Yeah That is, it turns out that
здесь причём Ага То есть получается
you can kill a neighboring country, destroy
можно убить соседнюю страну разрушить у
everything for it, and in short, your children live
неё всё и короче и твои дети живут
normally, and other children, too. Look, for
нормально а другие дети это также Смотри
example,
вот например
if I take it and burn it
если я так беру и сжигаю кому-то машину
I have to pay someone a car for this car so if I
я должен отплатить эту машину так если я
died for example then my debt as well as my
например умер то мой долг как и моя
legacy this is the Heritage goes to my
спадчина это Наследие переходит моим
heirs so if they accepted they
наследникам так если они приняли они
accept you are now talking about finances
принимают вы сейчас говорите про финансы
or about some kind of hatred towards the people in
или про какую-то ненависть к народу в
the sense of what kind of Hatred  to the people there is
смысле а какая Ненависть к народу есть
No well you I I am talking about the fact that
Нет ну вы Я я говорю про то что сыны
sons sons should not pay for the fact that
сыновья не должны расплачиваться то что
they are despised or hated for what
их там презирают или ненавидят за то что
their grandfather did not seri some kind of
сделал их дед не сери какие-то
reparations reparations sa moral
репарации репарации са моральная
responsibility there is also yes it
ответственность есть тоже да
turns out Well how stop Wait you to me
получается Ну как стоп Подождите вы мне
just asked about the Volyn massacre
только что спросили про волынскую резню
Yeah That is, you asked me, a person, in the twenty-
Угу То есть вы меня человека в двадцать
first year for some reason about the
первом году почему-то спросили про
Volyn massacre Why Who is to blame You
волынскую резню Почему Кто виноват Вы же
constantly ask me who is
меня спрашиваете постоянно к виноват кто
to blame That is, it turns out that you are
винова Вот то есть получается вы
raising some things Yes, it turns out that we bear
поднимаете какие-то вещи Да мы несём
responsibility  for what
получается ответственность за то что
our ancestors did and we understand that
делали наши предки и мы понимаем Да что
not all of them did the right things.
не все из них делали правильные вещи Вот
By the way, another thing that you accuse me of is that I
кстати ещ то что вы меня обвиняете что я
say something somewhere. This is a difficult question, but
где-то говорю Это сложный вопрос а
somewhere  I say definitely this also
где-то говорю однозначно это также
applies to you Where you say Putin is
применимо и к вам Где вы говорите Путин
100% guilty and the Volyn Massacre
стопроцентно виноват а Волынская Резня
It was very difficult, incomprehensible I
Это было очень сложно непонятно я вам
tell you it's very simple Look it's very I'm telling
кажу это очень просто Смотри это очень Я
you straight Volyn Massacre look in the
же вам прямо волын резне смотри в
Volyn Massacre both
Волынской резне были виноваты как и
certain parts of the Ukrainians were guilty and
определённые части украинцев так и
certain
определённые
parts of the Poles there were a lot of them and in the
части Поляков там там много было то и в
OUN there were some yes that is branches
ОУН были некоторые да то есть отделения
that took part in this Well you
которые принимали в этом участие Ну
see you don't name any individuals
видите никакой никаких личностей вы не
And when it comes to Russia
называете А когда касается России
Ukraine definitely not well look I'll
Украины однозначно не ну смотрите я
tell you why That's why you throw away all
скажу почему Потому вы выбрасываете все
this all this  these mechanisms processes
вот это все вот эти механизмы процессы
that took place back in the Soviet Union
которые происходили ещё Советского Союза
you don't throw at one person that he is
вы на бросаете на одного человека что он
guilty look at the Volyn massacre
виноват смотрите насчёт Волынской резни
I haven't studied this thing in detail in the personalities
Я не изучал детально в персоналия эту
so I can't speak for the
вещь поэтому я не могу сказать за
personalities Yes there Well I generally understand
персональ Да там Ну я в общем я понимаю
that yes there were uh let's say  act of
что да там были э скажем акт
resi prov prokh people both from the
реси пров прох людей как со стороны
Ukrainian side and from the Poles side it
украинцев так и со стороны Поляков это
was we admit it yes that is they had
было мы это признаём да то есть было у
ethnic Difficult relations between
этническое Непростые отношения между
Ukraine and Russia Here we are now  we are
Украиной и Россией Вот мы сейчас мы вот
here contemplating so we don't need to get into the
тут созерцая так нам не надо лезть в
Historical Archives we are here
Исторический архи мы тут
Contemplating horse ko vo in ukraine
Созерцать коне ко во в укра
what e the whole special operation began only
что э вся спецоперация началась только
from one order of the Armed Forces there is
из одного приказа ВС
nothing even Putin has no
ничего нет это даже у Путина даже
interests there is nothing it's just
никаких нет интересов ничего нету просто
his some kind of schizophrenia  No, look, I
это вот его шиза какая-то Нет смотрите Я
don't know Putin's motives, he's a schizophrenic, or did
не знаю мотивы Путина шиза или Там
his girlfriend ask him to take away
девушка его попросила отбить ему там
a couple of regions for him, for example, or something? Well,
короче пару областей например или что Ну
that's either he decided that he was the Emperor, I don't
то или он решил что он Император я не
know, I can't get into his brain, but
знаю я не могу залезть в его мозг Но мы
you and I can see from the facts that this is  the so-
с вами по фактам может видеть что это
called operation began as
так называе операция началась в
a result of the decree Yes, who is
результате указа Да кто несёт
responsible for this decree, that is, Here are
ответственность за этот указ то есть Вот
his personal motives may be different, from the
его личные мотивы могут быть разные от
fact that he is sick to the fact that he wants
того что он больной до того что он хочет
maybe his motive is that Zelensky did not
может его мотив что Зеленский не
comply with the Minsk agreements, for example, for
соблюдал минские соглашения например
example, maybe yes, like, that is,  his
например может быть да типа то есть его
his motives maybe we don't know his
его мотивы может быть мы не знаем его
motives so but he attacked he committed an act of
мотивы так но он напал он сделал акт
aggression That is if I came and broke
агрессии То есть если я пришёл и разбил
your nose
вам нос
so instead of saying that oh
так и вы вместо того чтобы сказать что о
this is guilty because he broke your nose
этот виноватый потому что Он разбил нос
you start  motives he's there something there in
вы начинаете мотивы он там что-то там
short he's there yes for example look you and
короче он там да например смотрите мы с
I Well we work in the same team
вами Ну работаем в одном коллективе
let's imagine you complain about me to the
представим вы там на меня жалуетесь
management Well in general we
руководство Ну в общем у нас как
have such a relationship
сложилось такое взаимоотношение
of hostility to each other and so on and
неприязни друг другу и так далее и
some moment comes that  I there, let's say,
какой-то наступает момент что я там
stole a woman from you and you
условно там увёл у вас женщину и вы мне
break my nose. And you, this is
разбивает нос А вы вот это
what preceded it, this is all accumulated,
предшествовало вот это всё накопившиеся
and so on. And you just want to
вот и так далее А вы хотите просто
say that he is a bad person. He just
сказать он плохой человек Он просто меня
took me and I have rights. If I, for
взял и у меня есть права е е если я
example, am
например
there, like  -that braid I look at you at work
там как-то коса смотрю на вас на работе
stole your woman and you broke my nose
увёл у вас женщину а вы мне разбили нос
who will answer Before the law you
кто будет отвечать Перед законом вы
who I who broke your
который я который разбил вам
nose or you there Well the one who broke your nose or
Нос или вы там Ну тот кто разбил нос Или
the one who stole the law will answer if I
тот кто увел законо буду отвечать я если
broke Yes absolutely So  that's right That's
Разбил Да абсолютно Так верно Так эти
why I'm saying these things of yours that's why I
ваши я и говорю поэтому поэтому я и
said I'm against war but I understand
сказал я против войны но я понимаю
why it's happening Look it's not
почему она прои Смотри это не
if I broke your nose it's
если я вам разбил нос так это разбил нос
not because you took a woman away but
не потому что вы там увели женщину а
because I'm a
потому что я
Gopnik I punched you in the nose  And this is it
Гопник я вам дал в нос А вот это
morally how to justify the aggressor somehow
морально как бы агрессора как-то
well it's because his woman was taken away
оправдать ну это потому что у него увели
if your woman was taken away it means
женщину если у тебя увели женщину Значит
she made a choice it's not like
она сделала выбор Это не то что Собачка
some dog you know took took away
какой-то знаете взял забрал
that's what Ute does in this
такна делает Уте в это
case No well I I I said  conditionally And
приме Не ну я я же я же сказал условно А
here is the big Geopolitics of two
здесь большая Геополитика двух
independent countries uh there are historical
независимых стран ээ там исторические
relations of the Soviet Union there the
взаимоотношения Советского Союза там
Russian Empire there the mood of people
Российской империи там настроение людей
in Ukraine the mood of people in Russia
в Украине настроение людей в России
here this has been going on for years for
здесь это вот идёт там уже годами
centuries and you want to say that
столетиями и вы хотите сказать что вот
yes look we have been living for 30 years Yes
да вот смотри мы живём мы вот 30 лет Да
there since ninety-first year there for 31 years already
там с девяносто первого года там 31 уже
yes an independent state you are an
год да независимое государство вы
independent state So you
независимое государство Так вы
develop we are developing like this two
развивайтесь мы развиваемся так два
young states and you They attacked us
молодых государства и вы На нас напали
because and you start to come up with
из-за того что и начинаете придумывать
some things there is no justification for attacking another other
какие-то вещи нападению на другую нет
than  if we
оправдания какого-то кроме если бы мы на
attacked you and the fact that there are people who do not
напали а то что есть люди которые не
agree with the current regime in Ukraine and
согласны с нынешним режимом в Украине и
they are subjected to violence there by shelling
они подвергаются насилию там обстрелом
is not a matter for
это не прит
people who have not given up their
слюди нес
vowels to the government and not
давам гласные с правительством а не
regime So we don't have a regime so people don't
режимом Так у нас не режим так люди не
agree with the actions of the authorities there are always
согласны с действием власти есть всегда
a lot of dissenters in any country in Russia
в любой стране в России несогласных куча
so But they are being suppressed really you agree with
так Но их давят правда вы же согласны с
this Navalny is happening on one
этим Навального происходит на одной
territory where there is 9080 about this
территории где там 9080 про этой
territory wants to separate and Let's
территории хочет отделиться и Давайте
wait Oh  you are starting now
Так подожди Ой вы сейчас уже начинаете
let's put Navalny in jail for not
давайте так Навального посадили не
agreeing Yes Chechnya wanted to secede
согласного Да Чечня хотела отделиться
in general they bombed Grozny So what
вообще нафиг разбомбили Грозный Так что
happened with Chechnya Chechnya wanted to secede
с чечнёй было Чечня же хотела отделиться
Yes it left the Soviet Union the
Да она вышла из состава Советского Союза
West also had a hand in it and the
тоже там приложили руку западные а
West yes that is the West the West bombed yes
западные да то есть запа Запад бомбил да
that is  what do you want to say that America has
то есть че вы хотите сказать что Америка
never
никогда не
arranged Chechnya look Chechnya declared
устраивала Чечня смотрите Чечня объявила
independence lived Independence and
независимость жила Независимости так и
Russia sent troops
Россия вела войска
there no You see you somehow look at everything simply
туда нет Вот видите Вы как-то всё просто
there are poor unfortunate
рассматриваете есть бедные несчастные
there are bad evil it was That is it turns out it
есть плохие злые было То есть получается
turns out uh Chechnya means
получается э Чечне значит
uh it is impossible to separate yes  in your opinion,
ээ нельзя отделяться да по-вашему вот
look, for example, you say
смотрите ээ к примеру Вот вы говорите
Donetsk cannot separate because
донецку нельзя отделяться потому что
Girkin arrived  can i say
приехал гиркин по Можно я скажу приехал
girkin arrived he is a terrorist there are people there and for
гиркин он террорист вот там народ ещё и
8 years these 8 years dont forget
8 лет эти 8 лет не забывайте там мозги
they brainwashed them and so on and so forth of course
им промывали и так далее и ту Конечно
they want to separate our territory thats
они хотят отделить нашу территорию это
not it and when for example he comes to chechnya he
нет А когда например приезжает в в Чечню
brainwashes people there he comes
промывает мозги там людям приезжает
well  not only that Well this is also not a way to
Ну мало того что Ну это тоже не способ
gather Yes people may have wanted to
собираться Да народ может хотел
separate there all this is to incite
отделиться там это всё подначивать
unrest this is how it should be
волнение идёт это это так и должно быть
Look yes let's have a very good I
Вот смотрите да давайте очень хороший Я
love this comparison with Chechnya and why There
люблю это сравнение с чечнёй и почему
is a difference in Donetsk Luhansk
Разница есть в Донецкой Луганской
region not the regional Council of Donetsk  neither
области ни областной Совет Донецка ни
Lugansk made any decisions about
Луганска не принимал никакие решения о
independence And so on it did not accept at all
независимости И так дальше вообще не
it was accepted by these militants
принимал это приняли вот эти боевики
who came to Chechnya official yes
которые пришли в Чечне официальные да
organ so it accepted about independence
орган так он принял про независимость
so there was an official elected
так там был официальной избранный
president Yes Jahar Dudai and so you
президент Да джахар дудай так и вы
attacked this America for example intervened
напали на это Америка например вмешалась
led  troops in Chechnya or in Russia America
вела войска в Чечню или в Россию Америка
never sends troops no so for
никогда не водит войска нет так вот
example or there Turkey sent troops in
например или там Турция ввела войска в
Chechnya or in Russia because of Torov
Чечню или в Россию из-за торова
wait  once again brought in troops No, she didn't
подождите ещё раз ввела войска Нет не
bring in no, yes, but you're bringing in troops here to
ввела нет да то а вы тут водите войска в
justify the fact that something is wrong here Yes, that's how it is
оправдании того что тут что-то не так Да
Arova, no, that's how it is,
так вот Арова нет так вот
uh, no, the presence of dissenters exists in any
ээ не наличие несогласных есть в любой
country in America, there are Trumpists,
стране в Америке есть Есть трамписты
there are these, well, there are Republicans  there are
Есть эти Ну есть республиканцы есть
democrats Yes they are even stronger there than
демократы Да они там ещё сильнее чем
people in Ukraine or Russia so
люди в Украине или в России так там у
they have such log cabins every election So does
них такие срубы каждый каждые выборы Так
this mean that we should send
значит ли это что мы должны водить
troops to support there, for example,
войска чтобы поддержать там например
Elon Musk, for example,
Илона маска например
by the way, Elon Musk saw that, he saw, he
там вот кстати илон Маск видели что вот
saw, yes  yes, that is, everyone saw yes, so
видел видел да да то есть все видели да
by the way, this is the same thing,
так вот кстати вот этоже пож Давай
please Come on, Let's finish with that example of yours yes
Давайте закончим с тем вашим примером да
It turns out that if there were
Получается что если в Донецке были
some dissenters in Donetsk yes What does
какие-то несогласные да Причём тут
Russia have to do with it, these are our internal affairs True
Россия это наши внутренние дела Правда
We don't interfere, uh, what did you have there?  -
Мы же не лезем ээ там что у вас были
then the rallies, for example, and you
какие-то митинги так например и вы
were beaten by riot police Yes, people were killed there,
избивали ОМОНом Да там людей убивали
like they were climbing up to you Okay Well,
типа они лезли к вам О'кей Ну также
that's why I'm saying that now and now
Поэтому я и говорю тепер так теперь и
you're talking about how people were destroyed there,
про вы говорите что там уничтожали людей
like that,
так вот
before Girkin entered  in the SN until 14.04 I authoritatively declare to you that none of these There protesters and so on did not kill anyone at all did not beat up the only thing was yes at the Ukrainian rally uh pro-Russian aunties who came Yes they stabbed a Ukrainian man uh so name it to me if you say that Russia Yes interferes because they killed something there before the arrival of Russian militants in Ukraine on April 14, 2014 on the territory of Donetsk Lugansk Donetsk Lugansk region yes name me at least some victims of the Kyiv regime if you name them I will apologize now Yes and I will say that yes I really did not know this I say again I went into chat roulette and was not prepared for such a serious debate if we appoint For example if we were I don't know if we had it planned In general a planned conversation and we would have prepared Questions and answers everything would be all we can we can plan write me in the chat your Skype for example or email there I will write to you later
до входа гиркина в СН до
plan this Booth serious debates
запланируй этот Бут серьёзный дебаты
seriously yes that is Well these are serious
серьёзно да то есть Ну это же серьёзные
things so people die in huge
вещи так люди умирают в огромных
numbers Yes but not for and your opinion is not
количествах Да но не за и ваше мнение не
taken into account and my opinion too Wait
учитывается и моё мнение тоже Подождите
yours is taken into account look if there are many
ваше учитывается смотрите если много
people Like you start to justify
людей Таких как вы начинают оправдывать
this passively justify so not  yes,
это пассивно оправдывать так не прямо да
I am for war. And even passively, what? Well, yes, but
я за войну А даже пассивно что Ну да но
this is not quite a prerequisite. All this
это предпосылок не совсем пути всё это и
is the general state background against
есть общий государственный фон на фоне
which your government operates. If
которого действует ваша власть Если б у
you and other people in Russia had
вас и у других людей в России была
a clear, unambiguous position. No, my
чёткая однозначная позиция Нет моё
government is doing it wrong.  the
государство делает неправильно то
state would measure these moods and
государство эти настроение измеряла бы и
understand about not people react somehow not
понимало о не люди реагируют как-то не
so it happens in democratic countries not
так это происходит демократи странах не
all the same look anyway all the same
всё равно смотрите как-никак всё равно
even in undemocratic all the same the opinion of a
даже недемократических всё равно мнение
huge number of the population it
огромного количество населения оно
influences because then
влияет потому что начинаются то
discontent begins so some
недовольства так начинаются какие-то
social ones begin
социальные
processes that were in Belarus there
процессы что было в Беларуси там не
people did not come out did they come out not rain
выходили люди разве выходили не дожа
a little not rain Well, you
немножко не дожа Да ну вот
see people came out in Kazakhstan people
видите люди выходили в Казахстане люди
came out there about Well Kazakhstan By the way, yes
выходили там про Ну Казахстан Кстати да
after that it took a course for changes Well
после этого взял курс на изменения Ну
because  takaev was afraid for his place
потому что такаев забоялся за своё место
Well yes yes that's exactly it yes that is
Ну да да вот вот именно да то есть
changes all the same any social
изменения всё равно любые социальный
protest it already uh changes the vector of development
протест он уже ээ меняет Вектор развития
state Yes to a more democratic
государство Да на более демократическую
all the same some concessions They go
всё равно какие-то поблажки Идут потому
because this spring can't hold on like that
что не может эта пружина Держаться так
well I don't  I'm telling you now yes there
ну я же не говорю сейчас вам да там
go out to Midi some condition I'm telling
выходите на Миди какой-то услов Я говорю
you at least for yourself Don't justify
вам хотя бы вы для себя Не оправдываете
because you justify there they bombed
потому что вы оправдываете там бомбили
Donbass Yes there is Angel Avenue but you don't
Донбасс Да там алея ангело но вы не
understand that Angel Avenue VS as a result of
понимаете что алея ангелов ВС следствии
which appeared look now there is
чего появилось вот смотрите сейчас идёт
a War going on
Война
so  yes, in the war now civilians are dying
так да на войне сейчас погибают мирные и
as a result of shelling by both Russian
в результате обстрела и российских войск
and Ukrainian troops, this is true, so where
и украинских это есть такое так вот там
there is some kind of front, yes, in Donbass,
где фронт какой-то правда да на Донбассе
wasn't the same thing,
разве не тоже самое было
it's not just Ukraine, for example, there
это же не просто Украина например там
some Poroshenko said about A well  let's have a
какой-то Порошенко сказал о А ну давайте
quick drink for example today in
короче бахнем например сегодня там в
Gorlovka That is somewhere there were people in
Горловку То есть где-то были люди в
Donbass petals are found on the streets
Донбассе лепестки находят на улицах
When Now during the war now in
Когда Сейчас во время войны сейчас
general whatever you want can be there
вообще уже что хочешь там может быть
now it's going on there in general  full-scale
сейчас идёт там вообще полномасштабная
war
война
now Are you sure that these petals are
сейчас Вы уверены что эти лепестки
being scattered by
раскидывают
Ukraine Well Russia is also scattering petals there
Украина Ну Россия и лепестки там
and Zaporozhye
разбрасывает и Запорожского
I'm just asking Are you sure
Я просто я просто спрашиваю Вы уверены
that these petals are being scattered by Ukraine they
что это лепестки раскидывают Украина они
showed you that specifically to
вам показали что специально чтобы
denigrate
очернить
Ukraine Yes I'm sure and where do you get
Украина Да я уверен а а откуда у вас
such
такая
confidence from you see  immediately became
уверенность видите вы стали сразу
Geopolitics you have some kind of clearly here
Геополитика у вас какие-то чётко вот тут
clearly sure how do you know that
чётко уверены откуда вы знаете что
there is someone scattering petals
вообще там кто-то разбрасывает лепестки
That is, you were shown a couple of stories that
То есть Вам показали пару сюжетов что
there are petals there Yes, I don't watch
там есть лепестки Да я не смотрю
TV no one showed a story
телевизор никто не показывал сюжет
how do you know there is barely here A  how do you
откуда вы знаете там еле вот А откуда вы
know that it's not you, not like that I look I
знаете что это не вы не так Я смотрите я
admit that both
допускаю что Это могла сделать как
Ukraine and Russia could have done this but I I I don't see
Украина так и Россия но я я я не вижу
the point this is my opinion this is not me
просто смысла это моё мнение это я не
becoming Geopolitics this is just my
становлюсь Геополитика это просто моё
opinion maybe it's amateurish my
мнение возможно оно дилетантское я моё
opinion is that  Russia has no interest in
мнение что у России нету интереса это
doing this, why? For example, so that
делать почему Например для того чтобы
people in the Donetsk Lugansk region
люди в Донецкой Луганской области
Wait, why? Why? Why does Ukraine need to
Подожди а а заче А за А зачем Украине э
throw petals on  some kind of Peaceful
накидать лепестки на какой-то Мирный
quarter in
квартал в
Donetsk So that those who disagree understand,
Донецке Чтобы не согласны поняли так при
what does it have to do with disagreeing if there is a war going on here
чём там не согласны если тут Война идёт
we need to deal with the military and not with
нам надо с военными разбираться а не с
some old ladies, right?
какими-то бабушками же правда
That is, it turns out that let's suddenly
пра То есть получается давайте это вдруг
break now and I have to
сейчас рвётся и мне сейчас уже скоро
go soon  mail we will exchange write
идти почта ми с вами обменяемся напишите
me mail and I will write to you Let's
мне почту А я вам напишу Давайте
Yeah I will copy and after that I will write you
Угу я скопирую я после этого напишу вам
mail well a letter like yes I will send Well so what an
почту ну письмо типа да кину Ну так что
interesting conversation so I I like Yes
интересный разговор так я я вот люблю Да
when people are not just there aggressive there
когда люди не просто там агрессирует там
And all you And here  we are trying to figure it out Yes,
А всё вы А вот мы пробуем разобраться Да
I don't quite agree with you So I
я не совсем с вами согласен Так я вот
think that you have this position You are not
считаю что у вас Такая позиция вы не
directly for war but you justify it with your position it
прямо за войну но вы своей позиции её
turns out because I say again I
получается потому что ещё раз говорю я
think there can't be a clear
считаю здесь не может быть однозначного
opinion here that there is some kind of Mordor  there is
мнения что есть какой-то Мордор есть
some evil person and everything started because of him
какой-то злой человек и всё из-за него
if it weren't for him but it
началось если бы не он а вот хороо мне
seems to me that it's good in place if it weren't for Putin
кажется на месте Был бы не Путин
Medvedev would have been the same but if for example
Медведев тоже самое было а если например
the person there who is hard
человек вот который там жеский
shot children in a school is it his fault
расстрелял детей в школе так виноват он
or society's fault  which
или виновато общество которое его
raised him there  for example who is to
воспитала там например кто
blame It is the school security
виноват Виновата виновата охрана школ
that let him through For example, it is the school security
что его пропусти например охрана школ
that let him
виновата в том что смогла его пропустить
through And who is to blame for the shooting of
А в расстреле кто виноват в расстреле
children, the one who did the shooting or some
детей тот кто расстреливал или какие-то
abstract nobody, the one who is
абстрактные никто тот кто
selling,
продажи
what is he even living in society, who did not
то вообще что он в социуме жит кто не
observe  that he is a psycho there and so on
наблюдал то что он там псих и так далее
Well, here's an observation, for example, if you, you
Ну вот наблюда вот например если вы вы
seem to be a normal person, and then you
вроде нормальный человек так а потом
go and commit some crime, are
пошли сделали какое-то преступление
you to blame or is Society to blame? That I
виноваты Вы или виноват Социум Что за
didn't
вами не
watch you, I am to blame, and so here, that is, it
наблюдал виноват я вот так и тут то есть
turns out that I think  normal people
получается что я думаю нормальные люди
don't do that I think Well it's not that
такое не делают Мне кажется Ну так не
simple we all do everything but when we translate it
просто мы всё всё но когда мы переводим
into who attacked Ukraine you have
на то кто напал на Украину вы тут эти
all these analogies here OTB
аналогии все ОТБ
and you can't say that yes Putin is to blame
и не можете сказать что да Виноват Путин
that is you start with the prerequisites and so
то есть начинаете предпосылки и так
on no Because there is look  there are
дальше нет Потому что есть смотрите есть
idealists and materialists it seems to me
идеалисты и материалисты мне кажется Вы
you have an idealistic mindset that there
у вас идеалистический склад ума что вот
is an evil Putin there is a poor Ukraine I
есть злой Путин есть бедная Украина я же
am looking for exactly the prerequisites some
ищу Вот именно предпосылки какие-то
reasons from which this appeared and
причины того из чего это появилось и
came about That is you who are a materialist an
взялось То есть вы Вы кто материалист
idealist I am a materialist and  being
идеалист я материалист а бытиё
determines consciousness or consciousness
определяет сознание или сознание
determines being being
определяет бытиё
being determines consciousness Yes, it
бытиё бытиё определяет сознание Да
means that it turns out to publish materials that
значит материали издать получается то
is, you say and in your concept then a
есть вы скажем и в вашей тогда концепции
person is not guilty at all. For
человек тогда вообще не виновен Вот
example, He killed because he grew up in a
например Он убил потому что он вырос в
poor family he grew up as a bandit so for
бедной семье он вырос бандитом так
example He killed he did not  guilty it is
например Он убил он не виноват это
guilty circumstance being
виновато обстоятельство бытиё
circumstance formed it yes Well and
обстоятельство его сформировало да Ну а
Guilt Guilt on whom lies
Вина Вина на ком лежит
here circumstances formed each
вот обстоятельства сформировал каждый
case private each case private Here it is
случай частный каждый случай частный Тут
impossible now Now to drag everything into one
нельзя сейчас Теперь всё к одному
circumstance formed
приплетать обстоятельства сформировали
Putin circumstances formed
Путина обстоятельства сформировали
Zelensky Biden all of us me you yes
Зеленского байдена всех нас меня вас да
Putin led troops into Ukraine  Who is
Путин вёл войска в Украину Кто
to blame Well, let's go You write to me on the
виноват Ну в общем давайте Вот вы мне на
puch It's just that our conversation has already
пуч пишите Просто у нас беседа уже в
reached a plateau that here Burn Who is
плато упёрлась что вот Горите Кто
to blame Putin I'll say now this all
виноват Путин я сейчас скажу это всё
flowed out of many y moment yes who is to
вытекло из многих й момент да кто
blame What to do
виноватый Что делать
Yes, okay Everything Let's go yes I'll write it off later
Да хорошо Всё Давайте да спишу с потом
uh  let's talk prepare yes about the Volyn
ээ поговорим подготовите да по Волынской
massacre about Bandera Yes let's talk separately
резне по бандере Да поговорим отдельно
about this everything come on tear it off well separate
по этому всё давай отрывай хорошо отде
yes I love yes such moments when people
да обожаю да такие моменты когда э люди
understand everything Well that's it  they can't
вот всё понимают Ну вот они не могут
say Who's to blame, someone is to blame,
сказать Вот кто виноват виновато кто-то
abstractly, some such
абстрактно сложились какие-то такие
circumstances developed Well, wait, then, uh, you
обстоятельства Ну так Подождите тогда ээ
can write everything off to circumstances,
можно всё списывать на обстоятельства
so every action has a surname, which
так у каждого действия есть фамилия
gave some kind of signature, which gave some kind of order, Yes, which
какой-то приказ отдала Да которая
did some kind of  then action or
сделала какое-то действие или
inaction yes that is, there is no
бездействие да то есть не бывает
circumstances circumstances They are going They are going They are
обстоятельства обстоятельства Идут Идут
going
Идут
And the troops themselves do not enter due to
А войска сами не входят по
circumstances That is, these are not mushrooms
обстоятельствам То есть это не грибы
that somehow grow Yes, they have eaten their fill of
которые както разрастаются Да там
spores
спорами наелись
and many people from Russia are not watching
и многих вот людей из Росси на смотрит
Guys, yes, you have several categories,
Ребята да у вас есть несколько категорий
those that  they are there for war, those who
которые они там прямо за войну те
are normal people, they are against war
которые нормальные люди Они против войны
and those who are, uh, for peace, yes, I am
и те которые вот ээ такие за миры Да я
for peace, I am for peace, they cannot say that
за мир я за мир они не могут сказать что
they are against war. Here they are For peace, they are For
они против войны Вот они За мир они За
peace and when we start talking, it
мир и когда начинаем говорить
turns out that these
оказывается что у этих
Zamir is a justification, that is,
Замир есть оправдание это то есть
some kind of moral legitimization, yes, well,
какое-то моральное легитимизация да А ну
yes, the Minsk agreements blah-blah-blah and
да бо минские соглашения бла-бла-бла и
the departure from the one who is to blame goes into the
отход от э того кто виноват уходит в
Minsk agreements, yes, but how did Crimea
минские соглашения да э а вот а как Крым
end up in Ukraine at all, yes, that is, again
попал в Украину вообще да то есть снова
going somewhere into history the desire to run away and
уход куда-то в историю желание убежать а
how for example is there something and so on that
как например там что-то и так дальше то
is constant constant excuses and there
есть постоянные постоянные оправдания и
are 10,000 of these excuses so they are all
их 10000 этих оправданий так они все
needed in order to determine for yourself
нужны для того чтобы для себя ээ
what what Well yes, not everything is so
определить что что Ну да не всё так
clear Like so and  it seems like you are
однозначно Типа так и вроде как бы ты
blurring there with Putin and this
размывает там с Путина и вот этой
company and yourself as well because
компании и себя в том числе потому что
every citizen of Russia understands that he is
каждый гражданин России понимает что он
guilty of this, this is how his country
виноватый в этом так его страна это
does it, and instead of
делает так вот и вместо того чтобы
accepting this responsibility, he thinks
принять эту ответственность так и думать
how can I be useful  in order to
как я могу быть полезен в том чтобы
change this situation so people ogat and
изменить эту ситуацию так люди огат и
they smear responsibility from themselves
они с себя размазывает ответственность
so on Biden America something Kosovo
так на байдена Америку чтото Косово
remembered And so on and so forth That is to say you can
вспомнил И так дальше так То есть можно
say a lot whatever you want there Kosovo
много говорить что угодно там Косово
Taiwan there Scotland independence
Тайвань там Шотландия независимость
a lot of things you can say but we see
много чего можно говорить но мы видим
That is precisely this fact  Russia attacked
Вот именно этот факт Россия напала на
Ukraine, that's all, but what do you know, in court you
Украину это всё но что знаете суде вы
beat someone up, the judge is sorting things out, and there's a
избили судья там разбирается да
debate going on, and you say, well, so
идёт дебаты и вы говорите а ну так аж
Kolya, in short, also beat someone up there
Коля короче тоже ж кого побил там
some time ago, so why are you asking me, like,
когда-то так что вы типа ко мне
But Kolya is like that  this is purely a
спрашиваете А вот Коля так это чисто
thug  approach so here is Russia it
гопничек такой подход так вот Россия она
has formed such an image of a
сформировала такой образ
citizen on whom
гражданина который на которого
Gop is projected it is necessary to deny it so it is
проецируется Гоп надо отрицалово ить так
necessary to push on Here and so on and so forth yes
надо продавливать на Вот и так далее да
Okay I think it was a very interesting
О'кей Это я думаю была очень интересная
and important conversation I really
и важная беседа Мне она очень
liked it so that is to say the person is not
понравилась так то есть человек не
some kind of  aggressive, not bullying, does not
какой-то агрессивный не быкуй не
treat Ukraine with contempt,
относится как-то с презрением к Украине
Ukrainians, but using his example, We
украинцам но на его примере Мы очень
looked very well at how people in
хорошо посмотрели про то как люди в
Russia cannot voice Who is specifically
России не могут озвучить Кто конкретно
responsible, who bears the blame Yes, for this,
ответственный кто несёт вину Да за Вот
Yes, in Ukraine, for all these
жение Да в Украине за все эти
actions, it is very interesting  I like it
действия очень интересно мне понравится
Write your opinion everything is so
Напишите своё мнение все так
Here are people from Russia, yes write Here is
ти Вот люди из России да напишите Вот
who is to blame Yes in your opinion and people from
кто виноват Да по-вашему и люди из
Ukraine can also write here in your opinion
Украины теж напишить вот на вашу думку
Well here I think the VPO will be unambiguous
Да ну тут я думаю однозначны будуть ВПО
yes who is to blame and the head of the matter itself write
да хто винуватий и саме головне напишить
And what is your opinion  the thought still chlop Yak Tsey
А чему на вашу думку таки хлоп Як Цей не
can not for example not voice that Putin
може наприклад не може озвучити що Путин
is to blame for the fact that VN in VN  nadavat This is
винуватий тому що ВН вй ВН надав Цей
an order to tsikavo tsemi mad dosu axis of such
наказ цикаво це ми ма досу ось таких
characters that we are responsible for them to
персонаж тому що ми повинни на них
influence us to
впливати ми
reformat them and those who
повинни и х переформатувати и тих хто
wonder reformat so that they
дивиться переформатувати так щоб вони
change changed from format I am for peace to
менялись менялись з формату я за мир до
format I am against What the Russian
формату я проти вй Яка росийська
Federation did in Ukraine O  so Slava
Федерация зробила в украини О так Слава
ukraine write to the channel if you think
украини пишиться на канал якщо вважаете
that this channel is done correctly you can
что Цей канал робить правиль ре можете
Zana os in opis PD video information and
Зана ос в опис ПД видео информация и
also ppi on Telegram also in opis video
також ппи на Telegram теж в опи видео
Slava Ukra we will win write to Telegram
Слава Укра мы переможе пись най Telegram
right now os VN and
прям зараз ось ВН а
pok this is very and very important YouTube  zana
пок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through srg or in your ban and very
нас через срг ор в твый бан и дуже
many videos I do not show to people at times I do not
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams That for
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
you we Mali operational  links are written
тоб мы Мали оперативный звязок пишиться
right now and
прямо зараз а
there in telegram we will find videos of other
там в телеграми окрим видео ще теж
interesting and useful information and we will oblige
цикава и корисна информация и мы повинни
you with constant operational
з вами тримати постийний оперативный
links
звязок
independently in that we will show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава украини
letter a
пись а